(audience laughing)
They're coming up.
Okay, I'll actually start at the front.
I'll start with somebody who's a staff member.
She can start a blog.
Give your name, or your dog.
Okay, my name is Espella, and I have two children here.
I have Elena, she is an eighth-grader, ranger.
I'm always trying to keep track of what I was forgetting.
And then Elias is a sixth-grader, so I'm gonna hand it.
Okay.
Hi, I'm Christine.
We have a fifth-grader.
This is our first experience as parents without finders.
And we're excited.
Hello, my name is Lydia.
I have my daughter, Rachel.
She is in
my husband and I, we work in the city.
That's my first experience.
Hi, I'm Oliza.
This is my husband, Lawrence.
And our kids are Lord and Lawrence, and they are twins,
and they are in the 10th grade.
We're the Mixon's.
Let's say we came to the Mixon.
We have two Mokai, just started friends here
in the cafe and then Levi is now in support.
Hello, I'm B. John Beharie.
My son is Nathan Beharie, and he just started high school.
And he is in our state, right?
Oh, in general, sorry.
My name is Moby, and my daughter's name is Kayla.
She's an English ranger.
Hi, I have
Dara Fana, and she in seventh grade
and exploring class.
Hi, my name is Miriam.
I have two daughters.
My older, she's in the ranger's eighth grade, ranking.
And Carolina, she's in fifth grade, so it's friends.
My name is Nelson, and I have one daughter.
She's in the ranger's eighth grade.
Hi, I'm Olina.
I do not have a daughter or a son, I have a brother, Moses.
And he is an explorer this year.
My name's Rixine Rees.
I have two daughters, Kayla in seventh grade,
and Chloe, the sophomore.
Got it.
Hi, my name is Dion.
I have two kids, Warren Gurl.
My son is Trevor Williams.
My daughter is V.C. Williams.
And my daughter is a sophomore.
And my son is a second grade.
Hello, my name is Jerry Gurl, and this is my wife, Linus.
We're new to the church, we're coming from Hollywood,
Spanish, and her son is a freshman at Follina.
He's in the portrait.
Hi, my name is Joyce Lake.
I'm here with my grandson, Zion.
It's not his first time in Pathfinder,
it's his first time in just maybe here.
So I don't know where he would be, he's in 10 grade.
Hello, everyone, my name is Camille Kang,
and my son's a fifth grader.
First time in Pathfinder this year.
Hello, my name is Homer Cauvin.
I have two students.
One is an adventure club, and my son Matt,
we just started today, last week I believe,
in France, fifth grade.
My name is Jorge Aguero.
My son, Adrian, is just started with France,
and I'm not signing adventures.
Hi, my name is Leanne, and my son is in inquiry,
and that's my fourth grader.
My name is Zizosa, I have a daughter, Melissa,
in eighth grade majors, and Adrian,
who just started France.
I'm Judge, the champion, my wife Rebecca.
We have, she's with the companion class,
Jaden, who is a companion in sixth grade,
and Alexandra is an adventurer.
That's all.
Hi, my name is Peri.
I have 24-year-old smartphone,
and I'm a companion.
Hi, my name is Ryan, and I'm a lay-on,
in sixth grade.
Hi, my name is Rosa, and I'm a daughter,
and it's all important.
My wife says they didn't really have anything to do.
Hi, my name is Marie.
I have two daughters, Sasha, she is a companion,
and Sariah, guide.
Hi, my name is Joanna, and my son is shot in front of France.
(audience chattering)
Hi, my name is Rochelle,
and we're my great mom, and she's in Poitiers.
(audience chattering)
She's moving into back.
Come on parents, come on in.
Are they coming?
They're coming, we can catch them.
(audience laughing)
I was trying to wait till after the start of the scene.
My name is Darrell Cummings, my wife is Rosa Cummings.
I have a daughter, Riley, she's a companion,
and Kendall is my silent niece, a ranger.
(audience chattering)
I have a hundred values,
and I have a friend's, Alec,
curious, and companion, Eric, curious.
My name is Victor, my daughter is an explorer,
and I'm a new son.
Kristin and Ryan, and I'm the other colleague
of this next board.
My name is Dweel Roberts,
I have a son, he's an 83, ranger.
And yes, I'm in jail, but I walked in the lobby.
(audience laughing)
(audience chattering)
Hi, my name is Joe
and my daughter's name is Nicole,
and she's an explorer.
Okay, thank you.
Do I need to bring the mic up here?
Speak up, I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Oh, she ran upstairs.
(audience laughing)
Oh, she came right down.
That's what happened.
She knows me, I know her, that's why.
She's being very shy.
I'm Kevin.
Well, it's very nice to meet some of you for the first time,
and I see a lot of returning faces.
Welcome to Pathfinder's.
This is our second Pathfinder meeting.
We've already gone over the schedule.
We've done a lot about camping and about Gillette.
So now this has been open mic time.
For you to ask any questions,
and ask what you'd like to know,
oh, they came in.
(audience laughing)
Okay, I'm sorry, this is what I told them about.
My name is Rebecca Villanterre
and my son is Gavin Villanterre.
(audience laughing)
All right, so we're gonna have a Q and A.
Before we start the Q and A,
we have our medical lead here.
This is the first one that spoke Australia.
And I'm gonna have her talk a little bit
about the medical form so that you can feel it out
and what she and her medical team
would really need to know from you,
especially if you're going to camp out.
So while I hand you a mic,
Travis and me using the second mic, B1.
Everyone, I think Travis up there,
and also, and these are information technology/AB staff members.
This is, I bet you missed her one.
Okay, just real quick,
I know a lot of you guys have already
developed out the medical concept.
Just a quick bug in the ear.
If your child has an allergy
or even like childhood, younger,
asthma or something like that,
if you didn't put it out there,
just give us a heads up of saying,
"Hey, I need an update."
Some of you guys would may call
'cause I just noticed somebody had a meth allergy
and I didn't know how severe they had an EpiPen.
It's not much of an issue
we have the medians here.
It's more of an issue when we go out on the camp outs,
'cause we've had it happen before.
Somebody had an asthma attack in years,
and of course, because of all the dust,
they have a lot of water there
and they didn't have an inhaler.
Same thing, we should prefer these food allergies.
Most of the time our kids know
they should avoid those things,
but if it happens and we don't have an EpiPen
or what have you, then it could be from an issue.
So just something to keep in mind,
and if you guys have any questions,
again, my name is Rea.
If you wanna get in touch with me,
just let me go.
And while I'm here and if you guys are medical
and wanna help out while we're on our camping trips,
that would be spectacular.
So we have a medical team
and they take turns being the one on duty,
and we normally have a tent that's just for medical.
So she's asking if any of you are medical,
if you wouldn't mind being part of that,
for people that take some of that.
- Dr. Nurse EMT.
- All right, great.
I see a couple more faces,
but I think maybe I should stop at this point
and not run around.
But all right, so now we're gonna open it for Q&A,
and I think I can just use this one line.
Any questions that you all have?
Raise your hand and I'll come to you with a microphone
and you can ask away.
Is that a question back here?
Did you raise your hand?
Oh no, okay, I have it.
Oh, that's your microphone there.
How do you point to your wife to have a question?
Okay, nice.
You do have a question for me.
- Um, well, if you were in your office.
- Okay, so.
- I don't know if you can ask me all the time.
- Okay.
- I'll be right back.
- So I'd like to recap.
All right, so quick question.
How many of you were here last week?
So there's quite a few.
Okay, let's do this.
How many of you did not hear last week's talk?
(audience murmurs)
It was mentioned last week something about
then having a tense honor or a happy honor or something.
So I'm going to use the pen words at the beginning
of this next month.
And I was confused about whether it was a good night
and then somebody mentioned like,
maybe some of the other forms attached to the act.
So, good question.
(audience murmurs)
Okay.
So the question is about, she has a friend,
and the question is about the friend's interest
in camping, my colleagues, what you're asking.
So, let me get one of the papers here.
One second.
I'm just gonna get the calendar.
I should have the dates all memorized,
but in case I'm wrong, I'm gonna have those.
So we're having a social,
and it's consisting of a club meeting.
And the date is September 9, I believe,
but I just wanna have it in my hand.
- Yeah, that's correct.
- It is, okay.
So it is, it's September 9.
So we're gonna have a club meeting at four.
Club meeting is from four to 6.30.
The kids will always come back in here
as they finish club meeting,
and we'll end the club meeting.
Then we'll start the social.
The social will start off with a small worship,
a short worship, and then from there,
we'll dismiss them back to the rooms for the social.
So the friends, for the social part,
will go straight out to the back.
Do you know where the lower east center is?
So the lower east center, there's some disposal
or garbage dairies and some trailers,
and then there's a big field.
So I think if you just go straight back,
you'll see the field.
The friends will be camping overnight,
and we're doing that as an intro to friends camping.
Most of these kids have not camped,
and we don't wanna take them away to a camp
and have it their first experience.
We want it to be here, where they're comfortable,
where they need to go inside the building.
In the past, we've had a child cry
quietly just not used to being in a tent,
and we were able to bring her into the lower east center.
We're able to call the parent,
because all of you live semi-linear body,
and we've just found that's the easiest way
to introduce them, how to put up their tents,
how to get into their sleeping bags.
Rolling up a sleeping bag is such a big deal to them.
It's hard, and even parents have a hard time
rolling them back up.
It's okay, you don't have to roll them back
and put them in the small bag that they came in.
You just learn to roll it up, that type of thing.
But that's what this thing is about.
They are staying overnight, yes.
Okay, no, no, no.
So the question is what about volunteers?
So yes, parents, if you would like to stay overnight
with your child in the tent, you are more than welcome to.
We just need to make sure that you've done
what's called Stirling Volunteers,
and that is a program online,
it's about a 45 minute to an hour training,
training on child safety, on how to take care of kids,
and once you answer all the questions,
then you'll pass, and then it'll ask you
for a background check.
It'll ask for your social security,
or your, okay, and then they'll ask for something,
and they'll do a background check on you,
and then the conference will let us know,
yes, this person is fine,
and then you're able to stay overnight.
So that's the process for parent health risk.
We do need to have you Stirling Volunteer,
and you can't wait the day before,
because the conference still has to clear it.
So no later than three or four days before,
and that gives the conference time to clear the meeting.
But yes, so in the past, it's normally,
in the past we've had most of them,
each of the kids have their family there with them.
Sometimes it's a whole family,
sometimes it's just one parent,
but the kids can bring their own tents.
This is friends, if they are comfortable
in camping on their own in a little pup tent, that's fine.
But again, this being the first time,
I would suggest either come with them,
or parents come to them,
or you know, you stay during the day through the evening,
and if they're okay, you know, you tuck them into bed,
I'll come back in the morning, that's fine, also.
But again, you know your child's comfort level,
and especially these are new kids,
they don't really know much about path liners.
Again, we will try to teach them some camping skills,
but it's mainly about getting comfortable
sleeping in a tent overnight.
If they want to tent with friends, that's fine,
as long as all parents of those friends
that want to camp together agree to it.
So let's say three boys want to tent together,
we need to get permission from those parents,
all three boys, that yes,
they can sleep together overnight.
Or same thing with girls,
of course it's girls with girls, boys with boys.
And if it's a parent, it doesn't matter,
it can be a daughter with a daughter,
or a son with a mother, that's fine,
but there cannot be other kids in your tent with you,
it's just gotta be your child.
And those are rules for the conference.
So they'll be camping overnight,
they'll have pizza for dinner,
then they'll do activities, it's a social,
so we want them to get to know each other,
especially their classes.
In the past we've been able to do a social
with the whole club, it's just,
you know, we're 215 right now,
and it's kind of hard to get them to all things,
but especially with their classes.
I think the friends have 40, over 40,
same thing with the family,
each of our classes are getting 40 and above,
that's enough people to socialize with and get to know.
And some of the classes, in addition to the friends,
it depends on the counselor,
they have decided that they want to stay over
and have a walk-in.
So we used to do a walk-in for the whole club,
and again, we're just too big to put everybody overnight here.
So it really depends on the counselor,
and the counselors will be letting you know
and shoot in your group chat.
Chat me, where is it now?
Chat with me.
Anyway, in your group chat, got it right, the third time,
they'll be letting you know whether you'll be staying
overnight or if you'll just be doing the social that evening
and what time you think of your child.
And again, this is optional,
some kids are not, they're very shy
when it comes to social,
but this is really a good way for them to get to bond
and get to know other kids.
Camping and sleeping overnight,
spending hours together playing games,
best way to make friends.
And I would highly suggest having your kid be a part of it
because they'll really get a head start
on having a body with other kids in their class.
So once they stay overnight, in the morning,
you know, we'll have them revelry,
I don't know, we'll do the duh duh duh duh duh duh duh.
But we'll wake them up and then we'll have breakfast
or breakfast will be in the lower east center.
It'll be a filling breakfast
because then they're going to be doing a swimming water.
And it's called basic water safety.
We'll be walking them over in groups
over to the Florida living pool that's over there.
So we've got that reserved,
I believe it's from 91, that's when we reserved it.
So when we're bringing the kids over,
we're not asking them to have major swimming skills.
This is basic water safety.
We just want to know that they can float on their back
for 10 seconds or they can tread water,
you know, for another 10 seconds,
that they're comfortable with diving down into the pool
and grabbing an object off the bottom of the floor
of the pool, little simple things like that
that they can do, yeah, just float on their back for a while.
We just want to be able to know if they're in trouble,
they can do these things because we've taught them
until somebody arrives to help them.
So that's all these skills are basic water safety.
And again, we'll help them.
I know in the past when I taught them,
we've had some kids, they really can't float
and it just boggles my mind,
but there's some kids who hold them
and then they just go poo all the way down.
And when we kept trying this, hold your breath,
hold your breath, I know this one boy,
and he was all on muscle, he was older while on muscle.
And I'm holding my breath, she's sure I can.
Anyway, we did pass him,
but at least we learned how to tread water
and how to doggy paddle.
Those are the types of skills
that we're gonna try and teach them.
So we want to tell the kids don't stress out
if you don't pass one of the skills,
we will work with you on that.
And again, they're simple skills.
They're not swimming across the swimming pool and back,
that's beginners, sort of.
We're just doing basic water safety.
So basic water safety,
and I believe they will be doing either a class requirement
when you're not doing swimming or an honor,
and we'll just keep rotating the kids that way.
And as we get a little closer,
it'll all be in the groupie chat
as to what time you can pick up your child,
and yes, we'll have probably a little snack for them,
'cause we'll assist them around lunchtime,
but that's the plan for the weekend, in a nutshell.
Does everyone have any questions
on that weekend for the friends so far?
It's a fun weekend.
It's a fun weekend for the kids.
The staff are on a jury eye in the morning,
but not as bad when it's during the tense,
'cause they tend to fall asleep.
It's the ones that are in the walk-in overnight.
Those kids don't sleep, but it's a walk-in,
and we enjoy the time with the kids.
Like I knew the guide class, they are gonna do a walk-in,
and I believe they will be in the youth center.
Boys are gonna be downstairs, girls will be upstairs.
So they're gonna play games 'til around midnight,
and they may change this, so don't take this as solid.
This is really what's gonna happen.
And then after midnight, they're gonna do
a little agape feast, or maybe around 11, 30.
Some cheese, some breads, some crackers,
and they're just gonna worship together at midnight,
and they can go to sleep after that.
So different activities for the kids.
And I see some smiling, I don't know,
are they gonna be awake?
Oh yes, they're awake.
These kids stay awake.
Even the young ones that normally go to sleep early,
they are just crying away.
They're so excited about these activities.
So again, we'll let you know which classes
will stay awake, and which ones will just do a social
until 11 or 12 at night.
Thank you, that's a good question.
All right, any other questions?
Yes.
- Well, my question is for me,
I think I'll count out this year, 15, actually.
I was not able to be in the meeting last week.
So, I think Dylan's like a summer in the morning.
- Okay, he's finding a recap on Gillette.
So Gillette is the international campery
that happens every five years.
It's like the Mecca, it's the heaven for pathfinders,
it's as close to heaven as you can get,
of course it's very far from heaven,
but this is what all the bad guys wanna do.
It's every five years, it's an international campery
where clubs from all around the world meet,
and thousands and thousands and thousands and thousands
of pathfinders are gathered together.
This year is gonna be in Gillette, Wyoming.
Normally, in the past many years,
it's been in Oshkosh, Wisconsin.
We're moving to Wyoming, and we will figure out
how to transport all the kids there.
We are trying to get flights,
and nothing's available at this point.
I mentioned last week, we tried to charter a plane,
and we were told we could charter the plane,
but they were gonna charge us 1,297 per person.
And we're like, nevermind, we don't need to charter a plane.
We will just figure out how to get everybody out there.
So what I told all the parents is,
if you're planning to go out there on your own
and do a little bit of a vacation ahead of time,
then grab your own tickets if you'd like,
or if you're gonna drive out there,
let us know we don't need tickets, that type of thing.
As we get closer, I believe by next month
and the following month,
we should be seeing some flights on there.
Last year, we saw flights around that time
being about $400 to $600, and that was last year,
so we don't know what the flights are gonna be this year.
We have budgeted for $750 per person,
and we hope it's not gonna go too much higher than that.
When we do the costs for each person to go,
if there's no fundraising and no discounts or nothing,
we figured it would cost about $14.50 per person to go.
$14.50, now we are going to try and subsidize
the pathfinders as much as we can.
We're aiming, we think we could do $12.50
for each of the pathfinders,
but we're hoping to raise enough money
to bring that down even further.
So we used to say it was $800,
well, that was two years ago, it's not $800 anymore,
even just food costs have gone up a lot.
Anything has gone up, everything has gone up.
And so again, $12.50 to $14.50
if there are no subsidies.
We have a bunch of teams that are working together.
We've got a fundraising team, we've got a financial team.
We have different people that are working
and trying to get donations from either businesses
or people that want to give donations.
If you know of anybody or anyone that would like to sponsor,
even if it's sponsoring one child
that can't do it on their own
or if it's sponsoring a t-shirt,
we like to wear the same t-shirt each day
so we can see our kids.
And it looks really sharp when you have everyone.
We were able to do that last year.
Each day we had a different colored shirt
and had the logo on the front and different size
and on the back is a forest lake pathfinders Florida.
So anytime the kids are running off,
you can see on the back, that's our kid,
that's our kid, that's our kid, very helpful.
So we're asking for sponsors for that.
That would be about $4,000 to $4,500 for a sponsor.
We put the sponsors logo on the back.
So it's good advertising for them.
Everybody around the world can see their logo.
If they want to share the cost with another company,
we can put two logos on there.
A family has already sent those sponsors
so if they want, we'll put their name on there.
Last year, a family sponsor, they're like,
"Yeah, I want to put her name just before
"state pathfinders on the back."
So again, if you know of anyone that's willing to sponsor,
even if they would like to sponsor,
we get a backpack or sling pack for each kid.
And I should have brought copies of those.
I mean, I should have brought samples of those.
We give them a sling pack.
So we give them what's called a spag
and that includes the shirts.
There's a sling pack.
We try to include some kind of a water bottle
or something to drink from that's forest lake pathfinders
that use the water cold.
And we also try to somehow keep their lunches cold,
their lunch pack or one of those cooler foldable bags.
So some of the swag that we work out is that.
We will also be doing pins.
Pins are a big thing.
And when they're, I mean, nothing about pins.
I mean, I knew about pins, but I didn't know.
I was like, "Oh my goodness, it's like a train crack."
'Cause they would go to each other.
You got pins, you got pins?
And they would just keep training.
Even my little inventor who didn't know anything,
he was like the most person,
one that was the most trainable with all their people.
He didn't mind going up to adults and asking for a pin.
And the cuter you are, the cooler you are,
the more you get pins.
So, you know, send your little ones out there
and you can get pins for your older kids.
But pins is something they do and they learn honors.
They do a lot of activities there.
I mentioned last week, I was with the teen boys
and I went with them wherever they went.
And we always went to some water thing.
We went sailing, we did paddling, we did anything water
is what we did every day.
And it's tiring to keep up with a bunch of teen boys,
but you know, you'll be going with your kid most likely.
And whatever that kid decides to do,
we'll put it into a group with other children.
So those water sports are what they like.
And it's usually for varsity.
The water sports are usually just for varsity,
just know that.
But I know some of the younger kids wanted to go to the YMCA.
Some of the younger kids, I believe,
there's going to be horseback riding.
So many different activities every day.
You will not run out of them to peace.
In fact, your kids will be like,
"Oh, we're going to do them all."
But they'll have to choose what activity they'd like to do.
Yes.
- Okay, I guess it's a final.
So let's say that I get it.
- Okay.
- With my five.
Let's say that I get it here.
How do I make it work to make it
more weighty, by the way?
I just want you to say,
"I pay you an interest,
"I pay you a different fee,
"or I pay you a dollar,
"can the parents work with me in the house
"and go to safety?"
And say, "Well, I don't want to participate."
Or wait for the moment.
How do you work with acting?
Is that an option for a car?
Are you allowed to work in the house?
- Okay, so the question is about logistics.
So it sounds like your family is not going to camp,
but you're going to be there.
Is that correct?
And let's say that it is.
Let's say that it is.
- That's an option.
- Okay.
- We want to put it on our pay options.
- Okay, yes, good.
Good question.
The options?
The options are you can camp with the whole club
as a family within a tent.
Or some kids are being like,
"No, Mom, I want to sleep with myself,
"I want to sleep with my friends."
All right, so there's a tent of friends,
and then there's a family, a parent tent nearby.
So that's the first option.
You can be a part of the club 100% of the time.
You're camping with us, you're eating with us,
you're walking to all the different activities together,
or keeping track of your kids as a camp, as a club.
So that's the first option.
That's the option that a lot of people will do.
A second option is if you are wanting to find a hotel
on your own and not camping.
Yes, parents can do that.
You can get a hotel.
If your child is with you at the hotel,
then they're not gonna be the responsibility of the club.
They will be with you at the hotel.
And the reason we're saying that is because
it's so difficult to keep track of the kids.
Okay, we're dropping the kid off with you.
Okay, we're picking up the kid now.
All right, we're dropping the kid off with you.
We can't do that with 200 and some kids.
So you're either with the club with your child,
or the child is with you and not a part of the club.
They're welcome to join in in what we're doing.
And food-wise, if you're eating with us,
which most people, I believe, will be eating with us,
it's much cheaper than eating out.
You can still come for the meals.
So a lot of parents that went, that just don't camp,
they would get a hotel room,
they would come first thing in the morning, eat breakfast,
and just be on site with their kids the whole day.
So they would go with their kids.
We're asking each parent whether they're camping with us
or whether you're off-site to put in four hours every day.
So four hours can be, you know,
you can sign up to be one of the chaperones
going to the different activities.
We're gonna need some people to help with cooking,
with cleaning, with camp duty, with, you know,
if you're off-site, a lot of people who sign up
for buying food and bringing it to the camp,
transporting food items back and forth.
And that's another option you can do.
You can be on site and do that.
But again, the children will either be camping with us
or they'll be in your responsibility.
They can come and join the club,
but they're not our responsibility
just because they're with you on your schedule.
Okay, yes?
- And financially what we do is just under the cost.
If you're not paying for food versus who you are, okay?
- You're asking about the cost.
So yes, if you're transporting yourself,
by yourself, transportation,
we'll subtract transportation from there.
Food, we always kept the food on
because everybody did eat with us,
but we can figure that out if we need to.
If you don't want to eat with the club at all,
I'm gonna tell you it's much cheaper to eat with a club
than eating out every day.
But it's not gonna be,
I'm gonna eat this meal with a club about that meal.
It's either you're gonna eat with a club the whole time
or you're not just reciprocating our records.
Yeah, question?
(audience member speaking off mic)
- So we're still figuring out the cost.
So he's asking if he takes option number two,
what would the cost be?
So until we know how much the flights are,
we really can't get specific costs.
Right now we're saying that the most it should be 14.50
and then of course that will come down from there.
And then I think, do you have a question about tickets?
How do you get a ticket?
So the tickets right now are already available.
If you saw on the link,
there was an option to buy your Gillette ticket
and the price was 232.
So that's to get a ticket to enter,
can't be sponsored.
That's to get a ticket to enter into Gillette.
So the cost per person, it's 225,
but with our link that the church wants us to use,
it's 232 with fees.
So that's what you'll pay on that, the 232.
And that will, that will be your down payment
and we will reserve a ticket for you to go to Gillette.
And then after that, we're saying,
please have that in by December 31
and then we'll know for sure who all's coming.
'Cause by the end of this year,
we really need to plan specifics and logistics.
So we're asking you to decide by the end of this year,
December 31, whether you're coming or not,
and if you are, it's the 232 per person.
And that means that you pay to the club
because we'll be buying tickets.
- If we have, so there are RB sites on property for us,
off the property, 'cause I was just waiting to say,
I know like even for Union,
the RBs were completely separate
from where the club was staying.
But if you do have the RB as an option,
you are staying in an army,
and you're not with the club on site.
Okay, so, you know, I think so.
- So if you have an RV, so what we found out so far,
Gillette does not have RVs on their campgrounds,
but right across the street, there's an RV park.
So yes, if the parents want to stay in the army
and the kids sit with us, they can still be part of the club.
You can be walking on to the side or whatnot.
If your child is with you in the army, then yes,
they're with you.
But again, they can still be part of the club for meals,
and going around with the activities
as parents are still giving their hours.
It's just a responsibility,
lives with the parents, coming in and going off site.
- Yes.
So the country is now world-conversary to our--
(audience member speaking off mic)
Question about adventure siblings.
So if you have a Pathfinder in Forest Bank Club this year,
as a Pathfinder that's inducted into the club, yes.
Your family can come, your adventures can come.
Now remember, this is a Pathfinder campground,
so there's not really activities for adventures,
but as a family, we'll be able to find some things
that you can do when it is going to a lake
or going to different areas.
You will need a Pathfinder van is what they have.
So a lot of the activities, you probably won't be able to do
because adventures won't have that band,
but the kids will still have fun, no matter what.
My little one just tagged a lot of mine.
I got my mom to take care of the blue one
when I was running around with the older kids,
but it does help to have someone
that can take care of adventures, little adventures,
when you're going with your kids to do their activities.
So yes, and there is a price,
they see the prices, and you know we sent that down.
(mumbles)
There's different prices for the younger kids.
So if they're aged nine to 12,
oh that's a two, three, two, and they're older.
So if they're ages four through eight,
they'll be charged 125,
and this is the age that they will be
on the first day of the campground.
So even if they're younger, when they are about
a month before, they will charge us their birth date
as to how old they are.
So a child that's 48 is 125, and then they'll add
three percent of that, and if they're a baby,
ages three and younger, they're free.
So it is the ticket holder stage on August 5, 2021.
Those are the prices for the younger kids.
(mumbles)
Yes, you can, you can go ahead and purchase your ticket now.
Single parents have already purchased their tickets,
and you know what we'll say is if you're planning
to go to the club and ride hopefully together on a plane,
that when you purchase your ticket,
we'll send you an email and we'll call you
and ask for each person's name that's going
as it is on your driver's license,
or as it is legally, and we'll ask for your birthday,
'cause these are the things that the airlines
is gonna be asking us.
So if we count on some tickets, which we will,
we will put in those people that we have
their information for, and you know, once an airline
sees that a bunch of people are buying tickets,
they're gonna start raising their prices.
So we'll be constantly texting and rudely,
okay, this is the price now, okay, this is the price now,
and you can send your payments in,
and we'll go ahead and purchase.
Or we'll say, go ahead and buy it yourself if you want.
This is the flight we're trying to grab,
grab the tickets yourself, that's totally up to you.
We're gonna try and get a little discount
between it as a group, and we have been able
to do that in the past, I don't know how it is this year
when they find out thousands of people
are fighting for Florida to go to.
(audience member speaking off mic)
So they already know what we call it,
and ask about the event, if you have discount
for non-profit, and they say, we already know.
(laughs)
Yes, and she's right, they probably have already been told,
but we'll see for sure as we get closer,
and see the prices.
So even for hotels now, hotels that are 40 miles away or so,
they're going for $500 a night.
So Gillette's very, what do you say, business savvy,
who are doing a monopoly on the hotels, it's not cheap.
I know some of our people have gotten hotels,
they reserved those suits, they became available,
and got a good price on them.
Now, they're charging a lot.
So several thousands of dollars to stay
the whole week at a hotel, like Washington,
and that's 40 miles away.
Some people have grabbed some Airbnb's,
I believe some families have grabbed an Airbnb,
where six families can stay there,
and that was a decent price, which just loaded up.
But remember, everybody from around the world
is zooming into this, every Pathfinder club
is zooming into this area, and Gillette's aware of it.
- Cheryl, I have a question.
How long has it been for active demand for?
- How long, what's the duration?
- Okay, August 5, 2011.
It's perfect.
I was like, you were just sitting here, I'm gonna get one.
(laughing)
- Can you share it? - Yes.
- Usually, usually it's schools,
I don't know, like, schools.
So, to flee, to wear, I mean,
to have a way, where, you know,
- Yes, I'm sure there are some.
- I have a filet in here, totally excused, but no,
my son said I have a filet in here too.
- Yeah, I've never heard of that.
- So, there is, there's a letter that AAT will give us.
I don't know if it's ready or not yet,
because it's a year away, it's a year away.
But there's a letter that will give to your schools.
I know Fleece and FLA and Poor City,
the admin schools around here will work with the kids,
and sometimes they'll just excuse the assignments,
sometimes they'll say, we'll give them the extra fee
to finish the assignments.
Public schools, not so much.
When we give them the letters to the public schools,
they're like, oh, this is great,
it's nice, but they're not excused.
So, you know, again, it's the first week of school,
they may only miss a couple days,
they may miss more, it depends on what school they're going to.
But you will have a letter that explains
where your child is and what your child is doing.
Good question.
Anything else?
So, Gillette seems to be the big thing
that everyone's thinking about,
and it is something you should be thinking about now,
because before you know it, December 31st is here,
and those payments are due.
And it's a lot, especially if your whole family's going,
that's going to cost quite a bit.
And so we're doing fundraisers.
Our first fundraiser, we have a fundraising committee
that's trying to get activities for the kids to earn.
The first one is September the 3,
and that is a weekend holiday,
but it was already announced in church today,
we're doing a car wash.
And the car wash is going to be outside the church,
and we're going to try and grab as many people,
we're going to try and tell the church,
"Come on in, get your car washed."
And we're going to do it as donations.
So we don't tell the need to pay us this amount of money,
because we find they need more than what you're thinking
you're going to get.
So they do it, they know it's for the kids,
it's for a good cause, and then we take that money,
and then we divide it up between the kids
that have worked that car wash.
We ask that one parent per child is there to help,
because it's very hard for us to keep trying to catch a child,
and children, when they get a chance, the young kids,
it becomes a game, and then instead of washing their car,
they decide to wash each other,
and then it becomes a water fight and a spray fire,
we just need parents there to be with their child.
And that's how we'll give credit.
So one parent per child,
and then we will have a sign in, and sign out,
we don't have to stay the whole time,
we can come here for just an hour,
but we will do the permit, we'll do it by minute,
as to where we're there, and divide it immediately.
So that's the first thing in the car wash,
we will, we're planning to do a man quick,
and it'll be just a nice time for the family to come,
dress up, and maybe the kids will bring a date,
maybe they'll sit with their class together,
I don't know, whatever that would be.
We don't have a date for that, we're working on that,
that'll be in the warehouse.
And we also have a fundraiser that's a walk-a-bye.
So the end of October, October 29,
we're going to have a walk-a-bye,
and start thinking about which family members
and which grandparents that you would like to
have sponsor your child.
So we will be at Cranes Loose Park,
or the one mile circle there at Oscemont Mall.
So there's a nice lake when we can walk around,
each time the kid walks around, gets a mile,
they'll get their sponsors ahead of time.
So for example, I told this last week,
my kids got my mom to sign up and have them give them,
have her give their $20 for each mile.
So my mom's thinking, yeah, a couple miles
for each of them, no big deal.
Well they each bought a lot of miles,
and at the end I think she paid a couple hundred dollars,
and she just wasn't expecting that.
But that's good, grandparents don't mind those things.
Again, they can get sponsors,
the kids will also sponsor each other,
so they like to fill up their sheet,
and they'll have each other's names on there,
all sponsored one cent per mile.
One cent per mile, and so it looks like they have
a lot of sponsors, but it's them sponsoring each other,
that's fine, every penny counts.
But again, think of all the different people you know,
it's a great way to get sponsors,
and parents, you can do it too.
You can get sponsored, and talk to your own siblings,
and your, talk to your growers.
Hey, I'm walking, I'm gonna be walking five to 10 miles
from all the spots you need,
and you'll get some money raised that way,
really good way, and the kids that are not afraid
to go and eat in church dinners, and ask,
they're gonna get all the sponsors,
they may get at least half of their trip covered.
Really depends on how these kids want to raise funds.
I know some kids already raised funds during the summer,
they were walking neighbor's dogs,
they were power washing,
and there's just different ways for kids
to get raised money for this event.
Any other questions?
Well, before Gillette, we have a fall camp out,
that's October 13th through 15th.
At this point, we think it's gonna be finally retrieved,
we've been calling back and forth,
it's available, we just happen to give them a deposit,
'cause we don't know how much they want to get,
but October 13th through 15th,
club camp out in the fall,
there's a little to the room we hope,
and we'll just enjoy our time together.
They'll learn camping skills,
they'll learn first aid skills,
they'll learn nature skills, and fire funding.
It'll just be a fun time to camp together,
to group with parents,
and you're welcome as long as you finish
your story with volunteers,
you're welcome to come and stay in the room with the kids
and be a part of the camp.
Of course, we'll ask you to help.
We have a famous doofy called Night Doody,
and Night Doody is where you do a shift
for about three hours in the middle of the night.
You're just guarding the camp,
you're making sure kids are where they're supposed to be,
if you see them out of their tents,
and if you need to bring them back, and whatnot.
Night Doody, we have three or four parents
doing different shifts through the night,
and of course, we have different shifts for cooking,
we have different shifts for helping with buyers,
or helping with the kitchen cleaning up,
a lot of different duties that we'll ask you
to sign up for within the camp.
So that'll be a practice for a Gillette,
that'll be a mini practice for a Gillette.
If any of you are very good with planning,
we have these different subcommittees,
if any of you are very good with logistics,
if you have anything to do with transporting goods,
like if you have connections,
well, if you have connections to flights,
airplane flights, please let us know,
if you have connections to trucks,
transporting goods out for here to Wyoming, let us know,
if you have any connections with foods,
again, anything that you have connections with,
T-shirts, making T-shirts, let us know, yes, Ms. Bette.
Were you volunteering, or were you having a question?
- We have connections with,
I have connections with T-shirts and,
thank you, so I can help with the,
I could contact some sales department
to see if they can do charter for us,
that's been a coming for,
since we are a nonprofit organization,
maybe they can help us out,
so I will give you a show.
- Sounds good, yes, please do.
If you have connections to, especially flights,
transporting things out to Wyoming,
like you said, T-shirts, food,
any discounts we can get for kids, the food,
we are thinking that since we have 250 kids,
maybe about 200 of those kids will go,
and if each kid only takes two people from their family,
that's already 600 people,
we're not talking about the 40 staff members
that will be going,
so we think we're gonna be between 500, 600 people minimum,
traveling out there,
and I already let the conference know that,
and the conference director, he was like,
"Whew, that's a mini city,"
and I said, "Well, I think it is,"
and he said, "You know what,
"that's bigger than most of the conferences
"that are going out there,"
and I said, "It is?"
He goes, "Yes, that alone will be bigger
"than a lot of the conferences
"for these other states and countries that are going."
So we'll have a pretty large area.
He did tell us that our campsite is going to be,
at this Florida conference,
is gonna be a one-mile walk to the stage,
so every evening for the program,
we'll be walking one mile.
Remember last week, I said, "Just start walking at a time,
"get your walking shoes ready,
"and be prepared to do a lot of walking.
"Every day, you'll probably walk at least five miles easily,
"easily five miles, more like 10 miles,"
and at the end of the day,
if you don't have the walking shoes,
your feet are gonna hurt,
but then you gotta get up again and walk some more,
so just make sure you have the right kinds of shoes,
make sure you're semi-in shape,
or at least you can walk for several miles,
and be able to carry,
you can do a backpack or a chair,
where everybody that has a holding chair,
those come in the end,
because you can just sit them anywhere
and sit down with rest,
and the kids, they'll just sit on the ground,
so they get a little nap,
and they'll sit on a lot of walking, a lot of walking.
So a mile from the stage,
that happened to us 10 years ago,
and it was a money, money week also,
so hopefully we'll know some of the weather ahead of time,
'cause that weekend, I wish I had boots,
that weekend I wish I had boots,
so the next one I brought my boots in,
it wasn't really raining at all,
but boots are good because you're gonna be walking
on these trails and roads that,
I don't know, maybe they're gonna be paved,
and it won't be an issue,
but be prepared, we're camping,
we're, yeah, we'll be camping.
The other thing you need to be prepared for,
we talked about it last week,
is port-a-potties.
Some parents have said,
"No, can't keep port-a-potties,
"we'll not do a port-a-pottie."
And I think I said one of the tips are
to take some baby powder,
a little container baby powder,
and you walk in, hold your nose,
spray it around a little bit,
and then you're fine, right?
(laughs)
I was like, "That's fine."
And then you've got your hand sanitizer,
which you can use that in other words, but yes.
We'll be camping, you'll be using port-a-potties,
you'll be using showers,
but Gillette is a newer place,
so they are building,
and they're still building items and buildings for us,
so I think the shower places will be new,
and they should be nice,
and hopefully they're large,
and we'll get a lot of people in,
and we will see,
none of us know which one is about yet.
Okay, any other questions?
Okay, anywhere.
- One other quick question, so,
parents' ticket is on the side of the array,
it's a thousand's room for parents,
and then a thousand, the children, for everything.
And then the question is,
so the activities, is that if we have a ticket,
does that mean we get to do all the activities they do,
or are we just there to guard?
- All right, so the question is,
if you have a ticket,
are you able to do the activities?
So, the open is a band,
and it should be the same band for everybody,
again, this is Gillette,
I don't know what they're gonna do, but yes.
All the pathfinders will definitely have a ticket,
and parents that are helping,
you guys are gonna be signed up as parent helpers,
we're gonna call you staff,
so that hopefully you'll be able to also do
all the different activities with your child.
But it's the adventurers that won't get the same band,
'cause they'll be paying a different price.
But the ticket again is $2.32,
and that's gonna be on site,
and then we'll tell you the cause for transportation,
and we'll tell you the cause for food, and et cetera.
Except for meaning travel costs,
'cause even if we fly in,
most likely we won't be flying in directly to Gillette,
we might be flying into Denver,
and then we might be flying to take a bus,
or we might be flying to South Dakota,
and then we still need to take a bus.
So, there's some other transportation involved
without just counting the tickets for the air flights.
(audience member speaking off mic)
Okay, she's asking what activities are offered,
and are they on site or not on site?
Any activity you can think of,
they will probably offer it.
Yes, there'll be some on site, there'll be some off site.
So, they have, at least in Oshkosh,
they have buses that will roll around,
and so you would jump on a bus,
you'd have to go to the bus areas,
and then you'd have to find the right bus,
which would be going to where you wanna go,
and then you get in long lines,
and wait for the bus to take you
to whatever activity you're going to,
and then the bus will bring you back also.
So, they've got it all worked out,
their transportation is,
once you park your car, you don't need your car anymore,
unless you're going off site to your hotel.
If you're on site, your transportation is taken care of
with those bus systems.
And so, what we've learned is,
what we've learned the hard way,
we would be like, okay, go out in the morning,
come back with your lunch, and go out again.
That's just so much travel, it's a lot of wasted time,
so what we're doing, some of our costs will be,
we're gonna give you lunch money.
You do lunch on your own, wherever they are,
there will be vendors, there'll be other clubs,
raising money, and selling the food,
and we'll keep you that cost,
so that way you don't have to come all the way back to camp,
especially down at the Nell,
or a mile from where everything's happening,
we don't want you to walk that whole while back,
and then go back again.
So lunch, we're just saying, stay out,
get your food, and enjoy, and then we'll see you at dinner,
and then together we'll walk to the worship.
The worship's are the best worship you could ever imagine.
The kids will remember them, the rest of them,
like, they're so creative, they're so innovative,
and they bring the kids in.
It's really worth it to go to
one of these international events.
Worth it for the worship, for the activities,
for the bonding, for the people that they're gonna meet
all around the world, especially with the pin-tree,
they love to get pins from other countries,
so you can walk around, you can go to,
okay, here's the conference room,
let's say, Korea, there's a South Korean conference,
and you go over here, okay, this conference here
is the England conference, where you've got, you know,
all these different countries in England or Britain,
and it just really is a lot of fun.
You will meet people that you have known from the past,
whether you went to school with them,
or whether you went to a church with them,
or maybe your parents know them,
you will always find somebody from your past walking around.
And I say, "Walkie."
Anything else?
We talked about it last week,
so we're asking about how we're shipping,
we have to load up, we're gonna put all your chairs in there,
we're gonna put your sleeping bags in there,
we're gonna put your cots,
we're gonna try and ship everything that we can.
And that was one of my things that I raised up
with the conference, I'm like,
"You give us two containers, that's nothing,
that's nothing with our kids, so we need more."
And they said, "Well, they have to be fair
to each of the clubs, and then they'll see what,
they'll try to work with us."
So we've already tried, and we're trying to contract
our own room, what do you call this,
set my trip to bring our things out there?
And then I asked the conference,
"We have something that could possibly do it,
would you like to rent space off of us?"
And they're considering that.
We even got better prices than they did, so.
We're working things out like that.
Any other questions?
- Cheryl, so all that's due right now is $232, right?
- Correct, that's all we need right now.
- So once we do that, you will contact us
with the ticket price, as in complimenting.
- Yes, so the $232 is the ticket.
As soon as we get those from you,
we'll reserve tickets for you in your name.
- Okay, so the flight, the flights.
- The flights, we don't know how much it'll be
until it actually comes out, yes.
And as soon as flights start getting up,
again, you'll be getting lots of texts,
we will constantly say, "Okay, this flight is available,
this flight is available, do you want us to do it?
Do you want you to do it?"
Some of our staff are saying,
"It just might be easier all around
just to tell anyone to get your own tickets."
But there will be some kids
that will not have parents there.
So we know that we will be doing some tickets.
When it comes to the younger kids,
we're asking probably best not to descend
the young kid by themselves for a whole week.
It might be overwhelming for them
to be doing all that walking
and offending themselves with food.
And again, they'll need the staff,
but the younger they are, the more I don't know what I would say,
make it a family event or at least one parent
and have that bonding time with your child.
And with the adventures, I think that I say that,
adventures need to always be what they parent.
So if your adventure is a helping hand this year,
which means they're fourth grade,
that means they'll be going into pathfinders next year,
we can say, "As long as you already have a pathfinder
in our club this year,
if you have an adventure that's going to be graduating,
we can let that adventure be a pre-pathfinder
because they'll be inducted into the club
the following month when we start a new club year."
So officially they're not going to be pathfinders,
but we're going to try and call them pre-pathfinders
and let them get a uniform, let them march for the club.
They'll still be considered the adventures in our eyes,
but we want them to be able to get a start
on learning pathfinders and getting honors
and let them go and do that.
Again, we don't know if we can register them
with the conference as pathfinders
because they're not officially inducted,
but we will call them pre-pathfinders and let them do that.
I don't know if that makes sense,
but we just want to include the younger kids.
But again, they do need to have an older kid in pathfinders.
We're not going to take the whole fourth grade
adventure class as pre-pathfinders.
They need to already have a pathfinder in the club.
So they're riding out of coattails
because they're older sibling.
That's already a pathfinder.
And we want the parents there.
So the sibling that's an adventure
will always need to be with their parents.
They will not be sent to a home or the group.
We don't know those kids.
They're younger and it may be hard on them.
They will need to always be with the parent.
I should just leave it on my phone.
(audience member speaking off microphone)
- I was wondering about the food.
Yes, if we're going to eat with the club.
You know, the club has like 200 kids, right?
They're always going to be there
just thinking of a rich young boy.
They're going to be neighbors or anything outside.
- Yes, so he asked a question about the food.
How are we going to handle the food?
So like I mentioned, lunches,
we plan to give you money and go to the vendors for lunch.
For breakfast, we'll have a hearty breakfast at the club site.
You know, there'll always be protein.
There'll always be fruits.
There'll always be some kind of starch.
We'll give you a solid breakfast
so that the kids have energy to go out.
We are still figuring out logistics.
What we'll do is for the kids that have activities
that are farther away, you know,
we'll say, "Okay, those that are going to the beach,
"you need to come and eat at this time
"so you can get in line.
"You have to go and get in line to try and get somewhere."
And some people will leave at six in the morning
to try and get to where they need to go
so that they get there when it opens at nine.
It's just going to be a lot of logistics
and we're working that through.
Food lines, in the conference,
we are known as having some of the best food
and we don't just, well, we might have to.
So we try to make it a little bit more day-ish
but when we've got 200 some kids,
they might not be able to do that.
But it'll be healthy.
It'll be delicious meals
and filling for breakfast and dinners.
And like I said, lunches will send you
to go to different vendors.
And there are lots of different vendors
from all different clubs.
I know that some of our staff want to do vending also
because as a vendor, you can make thousands
and thousands of dollars
but we would need parent help to be cooking
and that's just a lot of work.
So we're thinking about it,
whether we will do vending or not.
And then if we do vending,
we would rely on them all to take a four-hour shift
and cook and serve and yeah, it's a lot of work.
Let's see.
Good questions.
(audience chattering)
She asked about food coming and snacks and things like that.
Yes, we will be sending that with the kids.
We could hop into that.
Maybe just like a convenience place
to sell things and not cook.
Hmm, that's not a bad idea.
We'll have to see, yeah, we'll see if they do.
Right.
So I know that the conference is being sponsored,
I can't remember, I mean the Gillette's being sponsored
by one of the, it's either Pepsi products or Coca-Cola.
So it's either Pepsi or Coca-Cola that's sponsored them
and they have an anopathy.
You can't serve, if it's Pepsi,
you're not allowed to serve any Coca-Cola products.
And that's, I don't know all the vendors
that they have got sponsors for,
but I know those are some of the rules.
So I'll point out that.
Anything else?
All right.
You can go now.
I guess we're done with this here question and answers.
If there's anything that hasn't been answered,
feel free to come ask me and every club meeting,
I'll be here after we send the kids off,
I'll answer any questions for you
and then the kids get out at 6.30.
Something we didn't ask earlier, at 6.30,
after 6.30, they'll get dismissed.
If your kid is interested in drums,
we will start here at 6.45
and do a drum corps interest meeting.
So you can find out about the drum corps,
the kids can see what the different drums are
that they can possibly play.
But that will be happening this evening at 6.45.
That will last for about an hour or so.
So drum corps, they meet on Sundays from 10 a.m. to 1 p.m.
Sundays from 10 a.m. to 1 p.m.
It's a commitment, but you need to do a lot of repetition
in order to be good at drums.
That's a great experience.
Have your kids join, have your kids join drums.
There's also a drill.
We'll start that in a little while.
Drill, they can be on the drill team.
We can also have an adult drill team.
So many of you are good at drilling
or want to try and drill.
We welcomed that.
Our adult team last year pulled it together
in a couple weeks and scored first place.
So we expect this to be a habit
that the adults call this score first.
And then we also have PDE,
which is the Pathway to Biology experience.
That's viable.